### Resume



**Kenneth Brubaker** Enterprise Application Architect

I am an incessantly driven technical leader of the craft of software development, having executed at all levels of the trade. I have provided technical management at several large companies and directed and participated in important software development efforts throughout my nearly 27 year career.

### **Experience**

- Enterprise Application Architect and Microsoft liaison for 50,000 person global Financial Services firm during their migration to an external data center
- Designed .NET Enterprise Software Framework and Salary Adminstration software for 70,000 person media conglomerate
- Sole Application Architect for leading Investment Banking firm, having designed an investment trading platform and several full stack .NET-based application architectures
- Designer and implementer of distributed, load balanced computation engines for leading Financial Services and Management Consulting firms
- Senior developer on many industry leading and industry first platforms including
  - First C++ Windows application development framework
  - First Windows-based global money transfer program for a leading banking firm
  - First home airline reservation system for a leading airline
  - Worked in senior architect and developer positions on large products for leading firms in the Enterprise Mobility Management, Credit Union, Financial Services, Healthcare, Supply Chain Management, Defined Benefits Adminstration, and Automotive industries

### **Technical Expertise**

- Application Lifecycle Management
- Software Technology Portfolio Management
- Enterprise Reference Architecture
- Solutions Architecture
- Full stack application architectures
- Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery
- Software Development Lifecycle
- Agile Development practices
- Test Driven Development practices
- .NET/Windows Architecture
- Microservice Architecture
- Modern Development Technologies including Git, GitHub, Chef, Vagrant, Linux/Ubuntu, Redis, Docker, JavaScript, EcmaScript Standards, Node Development, NPM packages, Go language, ExpressJS websites, TypeScript, Angular, Babel, and WebPack

### **Selected Work History**

# eLead: Contract/FTE, March 2015 – Present (Automotive CRM) Enterprise Architect

- Developed strategy, principles, and reference architecture requirements for the microservice-based rewrite of a large SaaS platform
- Implemented core service technologies based on the requirements
- Implemented and oversaw deployment of several application services using the core services architecture.
- Prototyped Express/Redis based messaging system
- Shepherded several cross-functional initiatives including Internal Open Source React component library

### AirWatch: FTE, November 2014 – March 2015 (Enterprise Mobility Management) C# Architect

- Supported the AirWatch scheduler service in a very large SaaS environment
- Mentored staff on Unit Testing techniques and Single Page Application Web technologies

# Voya Investment Management: Contract/FTE, May 2009 – November 2014 (Financial Services) Application Architect

- Designed and managed the administration of Software Configuration Management (SCM) and Application Lifecycle Management (ALM) practices for 50+ person development organization across three locations in a highly regulated environment
- Designed and implemented three full stack application architectures using various Microsoft and web technologies over the course of my employment
- Developed Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC) in addition to the software stack for a trading system

# Kurt Salmon Associates: Contract, August 2007 – September 2008 (Management Consulting) Application Designer

• Provided analysis, design, and development of calculation engine for the rewrite of a performance management system including an Active/Active high availability cluster

### Cox Enterprises: Contract, February 2006 – July 2007 (Media) Enterprise Architect

- Participated in the design and provided the administration of Software Configuration Management (SCM) and Application Lifecycle Management (ALM) practices for 30+ person development organization
- Designed and implemented application architecture of new Salary Administration application for 70,000 person organization

### Fiserv: Contract, May 2003 – June 2004, July 2005 – January 2006 (Financial Services) Senior Software Consultant

• Designed and implemented code generation-based distributed calculation engine for leading NAIC Annual Reporting software provider

# Aon: FTE, July 2004 – July 2005 (Financial Services/Human Resources) Senior Application Architect

- Microsoft liaison and Enterprise Architect for 50,000 person global firm during migration to external data center
- Migration involved hundreds of applications and dozens of application teams across many locations

## re:Member Data Services: December 2001 – October 2002 (Financial Services) Chief Technical Architect

- Implemented SDLC and full stack web architecture using the just released .NET Framework
- Designed and implemented innovative (for the time) ORM framework and Unit Test engine

### Whitewater Group: FTE/Contract, May 1990 – January 1993 Member Technical Staff

- Developed several subsystems for first Windows-based global money transfer application using object-oriented programming environment including Data Access Layer (DAL), printing subsystem and virtualized custom Windows GUI controls
- Sole tester for first C++ Windows GUI application framework. Drafted reference documentation for Window GDI

### **Education**

### University of Pennsylvania

Philadelphia, PA BSE in Computer Science and Engineering Graduated May 1990

#### Certifications

#### **Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)**

Scrum Alliance March 2013 - March 2015